<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="configuration.xsl"?>

<configuration>

<!-- need to fill your crawler contact information -->
<property>
  <name>http.agent.name</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>'User-Agent' name: a single word uniquely identifying your crawler.

  The value is used to select the group of robots.txt rules addressing your
  crawler. It is also sent as part of the HTTP 'User-Agent' request header.

  This property MUST NOT be empty -
  please set this to a single word uniquely related to your organization.

  Following RFC 9309 the 'User-Agent' name (aka. 'product token')
  &quot;MUST contain only uppercase and lowercase letters ('a-z' and
  'A-Z'), underscores ('_'), and hyphens ('-').&quot;

  NOTE: You should also check other related properties:

    http.robots.agents
    http.agent.description
    http.agent.url
    http.agent.email
    http.agent.version

  and set their values appropriately.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.robots.agents</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>Any other agents, apart from 'http.agent.name', that the robots
  parser would look for in robots.txt. Multiple agents can be provided using
  comma as a delimiter. eg. mybot,foo-spider,bar-crawler

  The ordering of agents does NOT matter and the robots.txt parser combines
  all rules to any of the agent names.  Also, there is NO need to add
  a wildcard (ie. "*") to this string as the robots parser would smartly
  take care of a no-match situation.

  If no value is specified, by default HTTP agent (ie. 'http.agent.name')
  is used for user-agent matching by the robots parser.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.agent.description</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>Further description of our bot- this text is used in
  the User-Agent header.  It appears in parenthesis after the agent name.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.agent.url</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>A URL to advertise in the User-Agent header. This will
   appear in parenthesis after the agent name. Custom dictates that this
   should be a URL to a page that explains the purpose and behavior of this
   crawler.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.agent.email</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>An email address to advertise in the HTTP 'User-Agent' (and
   'From') request headers. A good practice is to mangle this address
   (e.g. 'info at example dot com') to avoid spamming.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.agent.version</name>
  <value></value>
  <description>A version string to advertise in the User-Agent
   header.</description>
</property>

<!-- active plugins -->
<property>
  <name>plugin.includes</name>
  <value>protocol-okhttp|urlfilter-(prefix|fast|regex|suffix)|parse-(html|tika)|scoring-opic|urlnormalizer-(regex|basic)</value>
  <description>Regular expression naming plugin directory names to
  include.  Any plugin not matching this expression is excluded.
  By default Nutch includes plugins to crawl HTML and various other
  document formats via HTTP/HTTPS and indexing the crawled content
  into Solr.  More plugins are available to support more indexing
  backends, to fetch ftp:// and file:// URLs, for focused crawling,
  and many other use cases.
  </description>
</property>

<!-- HTTP protocol and fetcher properties -->
<property>
  <name>fetcher.server.delay</name>
  <value>6.0</value>
  <description>The number of seconds the fetcher will delay between
   successive requests to the same server. Note that this might get
   overridden by a Crawl-Delay from a robots.txt and is used ONLY if
   fetcher.threads.per.queue is set to 1.
   </description>
</property>
<property>
 <name>fetcher.max.crawl.delay</name>
 <value>120</value>
 <description>
 If the Crawl-Delay in robots.txt is set to greater than this value (in
 seconds) then the fetcher will skip this page, generating an error report.
 If set to -1 the fetcher will never skip such pages and will wait the
 amount of time retrieved from robots.txt Crawl-Delay, however long that
 might be.
 </description>
</property>

<property>
  <name>http.content.limit</name>
  <value>5242880</value>
  <description>The length limit for downloaded content using the http/https
  protocols, in bytes. If this value is non-negative (>=0), content longer
  than it will be truncated; otherwise, no truncation at all. Do not
  confuse this setting with the file.content.limit setting.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.store.responsetime</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>Enables us to record the response time of the
  host which is the time period between start connection to end
  connection of a pages host. The response time in milliseconds
  is stored in CrawlDb in CrawlDatum's meta data under key &quot;_rs_&quot;
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>store.ip.address</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>Enables us to capture the specific IP address
  (InetSocketAddress) of the host which we connect to via the given
  protocol. Currently supported by: protocol-ftp, protocol-http,
  protocol-okhttp, protocol-htmlunit, protocol-selenium.  Note that
  the IP address is required by the plugin index-geoip and when
  writing WARC files.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>store.http.request</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>
    Store the HTTP request headers sent by Nutch. Useful for debugging and
    required when writing WARC files.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>store.http.headers</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>
    Store the HTTP response headers received by Nutch from the
    server. Useful for debugging and required when writing WARC files.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.accept.language</name>
  <value>en-US,en;q=0.5</value>
  <description>Value of the "Accept-Language" request header field.
  This allows selecting non-English language as default one to retrieve.
  It is a useful setting for search engines build for certain national group.
  To send requests without "Accept-Language" header field, this property must
  be configured to contain a space character because an empty property does
  not overwrite the default.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.accept.charset</name>
  <value> </value>
  <description>Value of the "Accept-Charset" request header field. A space character
  as value will cause that no "Accept-Charset" header field is sent in the request.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.time.limit</name>
  <value>120</value>
  <description>The time limit in seconds to fetch a single document.
  If this value is non-negative (>=0), the HTTP protocol implementation
  will stop reading from a socket after http.time.limit seconds have
  been spent for fetching this document.  The HTTP response is then
  marked as truncated.  The http.time.limit should be set to a longer
  time period than http.timeout, as it applies to the entire duration
  to fetch a document, not only the network timeout of a single I/O
  operation.  Note: supported only by protocol-okhttp.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.timeout</name>
  <value>30000</value>
  <description>The default network timeout, in milliseconds.</description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.redirect.max</name>
  <value>3</value>
  <description>The maximum number of redirects the fetcher will follow when
  trying to fetch a page. If set to negative or 0, fetcher won't immediately
  follow redirected URLs, instead it will record them for later fetching.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.redirect.max.exceeded.skip</name>
  <value>false</value>
  <description>
    Whether to skip the last URL in a redirect chain when when redirects
    are followed (http.redirect.max > 0) and the maximum number of redirects
    in a chain is exceeded (redirect_count > http.redirect.max).
    If not skipped the redirect target URLs are stored as `linked`
    and fetched in one of the following cycles. See also NUTCH-2748.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>http.partial.truncated</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>
    If true the HTTP protocol implementation may store the content of
    partial fetches and mark the response as truncated instead of
    throwing an exception which will cause the fetch to fail.  This
    allows to use the data which has already been fetched, instead of
    retrying the fetch later.  Note: supported only by protocol-okhttp.
  </description>
</property>

<property>
  <name>fetcher.store.content</name>
  <value>false</value>
  <description>If true, fetcher will store content.</description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.store.404s</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>If true, fetcher will also store the content of 404s and other
  non-successful responses for debugging or archival purposes.</description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.store.warc</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>If true, fetcher will write WARC files.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.store.robotstxt</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>If true (and fetcher.store.content or
  fetcher.store.warc are true), fetcher will store the robots.txt
  response content and status for debugging or archival purposes. The
  robots.txt is added to the content/ folder of the fetched segment
  and/or the WARC files.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.signature</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>If true, fetcher will generate the signature for
  successfully fetched documents even if the content is not parsed by
  fetcher (see property fetcher.parse).  Default is false, which means
  that the signature is calculated when parsing either by the fetcher
  or during the parsing step.  Note that a non-parsing fetcher can
  only generate signatures based on the binary content and not on the
  textual content. An appropriate signature class should be chosen
  (see property db.signature.class).
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.redirect.dedupcache.seconds</name>
  <value>3600</value>
  <description>
    The maximum time in seconds fetcher will cache redirects for
    deduplication.  If the same redirect URL is seen again withing
    this time it is skipped. This allows to avoid pathological cases
    where many or most of the URLs of a host are redirected to the
    same URL, eg. a page to login, accept cookies, indicating an
    error.  A value less or equal zero disables redirect deduplication.
    Caveat: This may break setting cookies via recursive redirect chains.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>fetcher.redirect.dedupcache.size</name>
  <value>1000</value>
  <description>
    The maximum size of the cache to deduplicate redirects,
    see `fetcher.redirect.dedupcache.seconds`.
  </description>
</property>

<!-- URL normalizer properties -->
<property>
  <name>urlnormalizer.basic.host.idn</name>
  <value>toAscii</value>
  <description>Let urlnormalizer-basic
  (org.apache.nutch.net.urlnormalizer.basic.BasicURLNormalizer)
  normalize Internationalized Domain Names (IDNs). Possible values
  are: `toAscii` - convert the Unicode form to the ASCII (Punycode)
  representation, `toUnicode` - convert ASCII (Punycode) to Unicode,
  or if left empty no normalization of IDNs is performed.
  </description>
</property>
<property>
  <name>urlnormalizer.basic.host.trim-trailing-dot</name>
  <value>true</value>
  <description>urlnormalizer-basic: Trim a trailing dot in host names:
  `https://example.org./` is normalized to `https://example.org/`.
  </description>
</property>
<!-- URL normalizers for specific tools -->
<!-- (Not mandatory if generate is used with -noNorm) -->
<property><name>urlnormalizer.scope.generate</name><value>org.apache.nutch.net.urlnormalizer.pass.PassURLNormalizer</value></property>
<!-- Required even with generate -noNorm -->
<property><name>urlnormalizer.scope.partition</name><value>org.apache.nutch.net.urlnormalizer.pass.PassURLNormalizer</value></property>

<!-- Configuration of scoring-opic: discounts on scores passed to linked pages. -->
<property>
  <name>db.score.link.external</name>
  <value>.5</value>
  <description>The score factor for new pages added due to a link from
  another host relative to the referencing page's score. Scoring plugins
  may use this value to affect initial scores of external links.
  </description>
</property>
<!-- higher discount (lower factor) for external links -->
<property>
  <name>db.score.link.external</name>
  <value>.3</value>
  <description>The score factor for new pages added due to a link from
  another host relative to the referencing page's score. Scoring plugins
  may use this value to affect initial scores of external links.
  </description>
</property>

</configuration>
